import type { MCQ } from '../../../types'

export const mcqSet10: MCQ[] = [
  {
    "id": 91,
    "question": "Which type of analysis involves analyzing textual data?",
    "options": [
      "Predictive Analytics",
      "Text Analysis",
      "Descriptive Analysis",
      "Diagnostic Analysis"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "question": "Which type of analytics recommends actions to achieve desired outcomes?",
    "options": [
      "Descriptive Analytics",
      "Predictive Analytics",
      "Prescriptive Analytics",
      "Diagnostic Analytics"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "question": "What does Redis stand for?",
    "options": [
      "Remote Dictionary Server",
      "Relational Database Server",
      "Rapid Data Indexing System",
      "Real-time Database System"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "question": "What does EDA stand for in data science?",
    "options": [
      "Every Data Analysis",
      "Exploratory Data Analysis",
      "Enhanced Data Assessment",
      "Effective Data Aggregation"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "question": "What is the primary goal of sentiment analysis in NLP?",
    "options": [
      "To analyze the structure of sentences",
      "To determine the emotional tone of a piece of text",
      "To identify grammatical errors",
      "To translate text from one language to another"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "question": "What distinguishes statistics from business intelligence?",
    "options": [
      "Statistics emphasizes understanding data patterns and relationships to drive business decisions",
      "Business intelligence focuses on developing mathematical models to analyze data",
      "Statistics involves applying advanced machine learning algorithms to extract insights from data",
      "Business intelligence encompasses a broader range of data exploration and visualization techniques"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of predictive analysis application?",
    "options": [
      "Determining the average salary of employees in a company",
      "Forecasting sales for the upcoming quarter",
      "Calculating the mean and median of a dataset",
      "Creating a pie chart to represent market share"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "question": "What is the purpose of sentiment analysis in social media monitoring?",
    "options": [
      "To identify spam accounts",
      "To gauge public opinion and sentiment towards specific topics, brands, or products",
      "To analyze network traffic patterns",
      "To measure the number of followers on social media platforms"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "question": "What is the purpose of feature scaling in regression?",
    "options": [
      "To transform categorical variables into numerical variables",
      "To remove outliers from the dataset",
      "To standardize or normalize the scale of input features to ensure equal importance during model training",
      "To create interaction terms between input features"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of NoSQL databases over SQL databases?",
    "options": [
      "Strong consistency",
      "Horizontal scalability",
      "Complex querying capabilities",
      "Schema enforcement"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  }
]
